Men are more conservative than women
男性は女性よりも保守的です
more traditional
より伝統的な
the second
二番目
highly educated
高学歴
less educated than
～よりも教育が低い
less conservative
保守的ではない
Turning into an adult is an objective determination
大人になるということは客観的な決断である
or subjective determination
または主観的な判断
did you say
言いましたか
Be an adult girl by the age of eighteen
18歳までに大人の女性になろう
you become an adult
あなたは大人になります
because they feel
彼らは感じているから
This thing is a subjective determination
これは主観的な判断です
He needs some objective indicators
彼には客観的な指標が必要だ
to match him
来配合他
what do you mean by making your own decision
自分で決めるとはどういう意味ですか
own responsibility
自分の責任
This is relatively simple
これは比較的簡単です
So everyone thinks this is not enough
だから誰もがこれでは足りないと思う
I appreciate
感謝します
over the years
長年にわたって
This plan
このプラン
Academia Sinica
中央研究院
main research plan
主な研究計画
and the Ministry of Science and Technology
および科学技術省
Previous NSC support
以前の NSC サポート
and social institute
そして社会研究所
Only when the funds are available can it last until now
資金が利用可能な場合にのみ、現在まで持続できます
we want to know
私たちは知りたい
The growth trajectory of contemporary young people
現代の若者の成長の軌跡
the second
二番目
Timeline of our positioning
私たちのポジショニングのタイムライン
from a life course perspective
ライフコースの観点から
from early teens
十代前半から
traced to
を追跡した
his young adult stage
彼のヤングアダルト段階
The third
第3
Of course we want to see
もちろん見たいです
Indigenous development model
先住民族の開発モデル
The pressure of entering a higher school
高校進学のプレッシャー
Results of cram school, etc.
塾の成績など
Actually that's them
実はそれが彼らなのです
really a second way of life
本当に第二の生き方
At the beginning there were about 5,000 people
当初は5000人くらいいたんですが
face method
フェイスメソッド
so we are lucky
だから私たちは幸運です
From our more than 5,000 samples
5,000 を超えるサンプルから
find some
いくつか見つけてください
Yeah, just retro and teen
そう、ただのレトロとティーン
do some in-depth interviews
いくつかの詳細なインタビューを行う
so everyone can see
みんなが見れるように
Our sample is 2,000 years old
私たちのサンプルは2,000年前のものです
Country One and Country Three
第一国と第三国
The third year of the country was the last
この国の最後の3年目は
The last generation of candidates
最後の世代の候補者
Country one is the new system
国 1 は新しいシステムです
under the new system
新しい体制のもとで
in the top twenty-five percent
上位25パーセントに入る
Chances of attending star high schools
スター高校に通う可能性
significantly high
かなり高い
So indeed reform
それで本当に改革する
yes bring some
はい、いくつか持ってきてください
greater inequality
より大きな不平等
family experience
家族の経験
What we care about is a structure
私たちが大切にしているのは構造です
a relationship
関係
parents divorce
両親の離婚
In the end the impact on children
結局は子供たちへの影響
what is it
それは何ですか
Here I will give you a report
ここでご報告させていただきます
College Graduation for Two-Parent Families
二人親家庭の大学卒業
relatively high ratio
比例比較高
non-two-parent family
二人親ではない家族
Graduated from high school
高校を卒業した
relatively high ratio
比例比較高
so here
それでここで
There are some differences in education
学歴の違いもあるけど
Let's just say family structure
家族構成だけ言っておきます
Is there any effect
効果はありますか
we know low birth rates
私たちは出生率が低いことを知っています
this problem is serious
この問題は深刻です
and marriage
そして結婚
Phenomena included
含まれる現象
It means that the society still does not accept out-of-wedlock children
それは社会がまだ婚外子を受け入れていないことを意味します
I remember when I was doing an interview
インタビューしていたときのことを思い出します
Respondents who were pregnant out of wedlock told me
未婚で妊娠した回答者は私にこう言いました。
He doesn't even want to marry him
彼は結婚する気すらない
Because he thinks he can't get along with him, doesn't love each other
なぜなら、彼は自分とはうまくやっていけない、お互いを愛していないと思っているからです。
Parents say I don't care if you love each other or not
両親は、あなたがお互いを愛しているかどうかは気にしないと言います
you hurry to get married
あなたは結婚を急ぐ
divorce after childbirth
出産後に離婚
Why young people lack
なぜ若者に不足があるのか
Motivation for marriage and childbirth
結婚生育動機
this is what everyone is asking
これは誰もが求めていることです
Let's start with family experience
家族体験から始めましょう
Early Family Experiences for Adolescents
青少年のための初期の家族体験
Regardless of childhood and adolescence
幼少期・青年期問わず
Are the parents divorced?
両親は離婚していますか？
In many Chinese families, the parents do not divorce
中国の多くの家庭では両親は離婚しない
but conflicting
しかし矛盾している
parent-child conflict
親子の対立
Early experiences of adolescence
思春期の初期の経験
Dating Behavior in Your Early Adulthood
成人初期のデート行動
what are the marriage expectations
結婚の期待は何ですか
especially in your 30s
特に30代は
We can talk about the actual act of marriage
結婚という実際の行為について話すことができます
usually tell you
通常あなたに言います
His self-esteem comes first
他自尊第一
bad grades wait
悪い成績は待ってください
negative impact
マイナスの影響
and always tell you
そしていつもあなたに言います
will continue into adulthood
大人になっても続くだろう
However, it is uncertain in the literature that
ただし、文献上では不明です。
after parents divorce
両親の離婚後
Children are less willing to marry
子どもたちは結婚意欲が低い
Or get married early
それとも早く結婚するか
Because if the child does not want to get married
子供が結婚したくないなら
because he sees conflict
彼は矛盾を認識しているから
Seeing that the parent-child relationship is not good
親子関係がうまくいっていないことがわかる
But some marry early
でも早く結婚する人もいる
because he felt he needed a relationship
彼は関係が必要だと感じたから
He comes from a place where resources are relatively scarce
彼は資源が比較的不足している場所の出身です
He needs to get into marriage
彼は結婚する必要がある
We pay special attention to this divorced family
私たちはこの離婚した家族に特別な注意を払っています
when he got divorced
彼が離婚したとき
Over 13 years old or under 22 years old
13歳以上22歳以下
then go and see what's different
それから行って何が違うのか見てみましょう
If parents divorced before the age of 13
両親が13歳未満で離婚した場合
Will affect pre-marital pregnancy of children
子供の結婚前の妊娠に影響を与える
But it won't affect your early marriage
でもそれはあなたの早期結婚には影響しません
Parental conflict high in early teenage years
思春期初期の親との対立を促進する高層
won't marry early
早く結婚しないだろう
High parent-child conflict leads to early marriage
親子対立が多いと早婚につながる
is it clear
明らかですか
But cohabitation and pre-marital relationship
しかし、同棲と結婚前の関係
more likely to marry early
早く結婚する可能性が高い
If you are with a two-parent family
二人親家庭の場合
And the group with low conflict
そして対立が少ないグループ
Parents' Early Divorce Experience
両親の早期離婚経験
lead to young adulthood
若年成人につながる
Negative effects of intimacy
親密さの悪影響
then on the other hand
それから一方では
It is important to note that gender differences in the effect
効果には性差があることに注意することが重要です
very obvious
非常に明白な
His family income was relatively high before he was young
彼の世帯収入は彼が若い前は比較的高かった
good family relationship
良い家族関係
And he currently has a job
そして彼は現在仕事をしています
He is more likely to be 28 years old
彼は28歳である可能性が高い
get married and give birth again
また結婚して出産する
For women
女性のための
If parents are divorced or separated
両親が離婚または別居している場合
She is more likely to marry and have children
彼女は結婚して子供を産む可能性が高い
but adolescence
でも思春期
her family income is high
彼女の世帯収入は高い
She currently has a job
彼女は現在仕事をしています
she is less likely to marry
彼女は結婚する可能性が低い
less likely to have children
子供を産む可能性が低い
If girls are fine
女の子達が元気なら
Compared with those who do not think that there are married
結婚しているとは思わない人に比べて
hope and desire
希望と願望
So what is the reflection of this thing for me?
それで、このことは私にとって何を反映しているのでしょうか？
Taiwanese family
台湾人の家族
In fact, many places
実際、多くの場所で
Or the impact between tradition and modernity
あるいは伝統と現代性の間の影響
compromise there
そこで妥協する
because of our values
私たちの価値観のせいで
between our actions
私たちの行動の間に
some are persistent
いくつかはしつこいです
some are constant
一部は一定です
So if say Taiwan
それで台湾と言えば
and East Asian society
そして東アジア社会
We are different from Europe and the United States
私たちはヨーロッパやアメリカとは違います
because you study a family in transition
移行期の家族を研究しているからです
Needs to go beyond your interpretation of personal resources
説明する個人リソースの範囲外である必要がある
should also be considered
同時に考慮する必要があります
The interaction of cultural norms
文化的規範の相互作用
Thank you Professor Yu
ユウ先生ありがとう
Please talk about Yujiao
ユウジアオについて話してください
you
あなた